

Precision System Design 180 Mt. Airy Road, Suite 100 Basking Ridge, NJ 07920 (973) 377-7500 – Fax (973) 810-1450 www.PrecisionSystems.com

### Rebecca Evans

#### **Precision Summary**

- 3 years Scrum Master experience; 8+ years IT Project Management experience
- At Carlson Wagonlit, functioned as a Scrum of Scrums, overseeing 3 Scrum Masters and 8 Scrum
   Teams (planning and tracking timelines, budgets, and other PM responsibilities)
- 8+ years overall experience in an Agile environment with some experience following SAFe methodologies (Certified Scrum Master)
- 2 years RTC experience, some experience with JIRA and Rally
- Local candidate with friendly personality and great communication skills; available two weeks from offer

# Project Management

Enthusiastic self-starter focused on meeting project goals, deliverables, hitting milestones and comfortable with clients, managers, customers, team members, vendors and stakeholders. Utilizing cross-functional problem solving, thorough communication tactics I work to mitigate risk and drive toward conflict resolution. A capable presenter providing status and solutions and experienced in both PMO and non PMO organizations. A strong believer in team motivation and empowerment.

#### **Key skills include:**

Organized	Strong Business Acumen
Team Empowerment	<b>Employs Sound Judgement</b>
Motivated	Goal Oriented
Skilled Negotiator	Vendor Management
Confident	Systematic Communicator
	Team Empowerment Motivated Skilled Negotiator

### **Career Highlights**

**Scrum Master**, facilitating product development, key Agile ceremonies, story writing review, impediment resolution and mitigate risk. Utilized Scrum, Kanban and Rational Team Concert (RTC). Coached to continuously improve and encourage sprint performance, story writing, burn and team selfmanaging.

**Project Manager**, executing project plans, financials, schedule, change management, status reports and sponsor updates, risk mitigation and planning. RFPs and SOWs for vendor management, finalize contract negotiations and fulfilment. Requirements, user stories, project schedules, data dictionaries

and closing documentation including lessons learned. Stakeholder communication, analysis, expectations and reporting.

**Project Manager/Scrum Master,** Rollout billing systems to acquired entities, integrate new versions to existing clients, new portal for enhanced user experience for billing

**Scrum Master,** proprietary online membership portal for life insurance and annuities management, new product offerings and new vendor stand-up. On-boarding acquired systems for Medicare claims processing.

**Project Manager**, web projects including e-commerce, marketing support, customer satisfaction, foreign language and accessibility. Successfully combined 3 websites into one, <a href="MayoClinic.org">MayoClinic.org</a>

**Project Manager**, DOE infrastructure transition project with 291 items including applications, hardware and lab equipment to a new deactivation contractor. Project completed successfully

**Project Manager**, on a team charged with the transfer of database warehouse (2 million names) as well as product fulfillment services to a newly acquired vendor. Deliverables included added functionality, new user interfaces with dashboard and near real time reporting, and the ability to cross promote subscribers and product purchasers resulting in an eventual 27% lift in sales.

#### **Professional Experience Defined**

# **USAA (Consultant),** San Antonio, Texas

01/2019 - Current

Scrum Master

 Scrum master for 3 scrum teams as part of a larger project effort charged with updating debt solutions.

Carlson Wagonlit, San Antonio, Texas

01/2018 - 01/2019

IT Project Manager

• IT Project manager for proprietary travel consulting software. Ensure quarterly releases deploy as planned, certifying Agile teams focus on prioritized work, and liaison between business owners and IT department. Manage software and certification updates.

**USAA (Consultant),** San Antonio, Texas Scrum Master / IT Project Manager 11/2016-09/2017

## **Key Projects:**

 New online annuities portal, e-commerce marketing trial, online and interactive service tools for new life insurance applicants, new vendor applications, other proprietary work

# Whole Foods Market/MDI (Consultant), Austin, Texas

03/2016 - 09/2016

**Project Manager** 

#### **Key Project:**

 Project Manager delivering Payment Card Industry and Data Security Standard (PCI-DSS) Report on Compliance, an annual endeavor for all companies who handle Credit Card Data

# **TEK Systems (Consultant)**, Paducah, Kentucky

03/2015 - 11/2015

IT Project Manager

#### **Key Projects:**

U.S. Department of Energy (DOE)

- Succeeded in controlling the expanding scope of the MOD98 project to transition 297 applications, hardware, and lab equipment to a new deactivation contractor by schedule updates and negotiating with department heads for resources to integrate change management. In order to simplify the handoff of the assets, I developed a transition process used to manage the departmental transfer, provide technical and functional documentation, licensing, SME review and signoff/handoff. The transition process reduced ambiguity, assigned responsibility and empowered the participants to complete the work as well as create a record of adherence. I managed scope to prevent further slippage and to meet the negotiated requirements to the satisfaction of DOE. The project successfully closed on the revised closing date, November 30, 2015.
- Rollout of the VMWare Horizon Client to replace the aging and failing VPN solution for new
  contractor group with 300+ team members. Utilized the VMWare consultant and internal
  resources to address issues uncovered by the test groups, established helpdesk procedures and
  user instructions, communication plans for the user migration, and identify applications
  requiring thin client delivery. Roll out was smooth and well accepted by users.

# **Zycron (Consultant),** Franklin, Tennessee

06/2014-11/2014

IT Project Manager

#### **Key Projects:**

• IT Project Manager, working with the development team revising client's proprietary medical billing software, roll out upgrade and facilitating infrastructure improvements with new client integration. The schedule included three upgrade rollouts each month. One challenging aspect of this was communicating with all the stakeholders involved. Usually more than 35 hospital's billing software would be affected as well as their system's ability to process all the changes in a timely manner. I led 2 meetings per week with the main objective being to ensure relevant

- stakeholders received the information in a timely fashion and provide a venue for asking questions. Customer satisfaction was improved and schedule was maintained.
- Scrum master, daily standups, Agile ceremonies, mitigated outside interference for the
  development team and worked with the product manager to complete the product backlog and
  prioritize work. It was imperative to make the software improvements, which were based on the
  new Medicare guidelines, in a timely manner as there were hard deadlines in place per
  government specifications.

Mayo Clinic, Rochester, Minnesota

1999-2014

IT Project Manager - PMO (2008 to 2014)

Managed multiple discreet and multi-phased web projects both small and medium sized while maintaining enterprise project management organization standards and policies.

### **Key Projects:**

- Medicare billing revisions and upgrades to meet new federal guidelines
- www.MayoClinic.org Project Manager/Scrum Master on large cross-departmental web project. A major undertaking to consolidate 3 extensive Java-based websites under one branded portal on a unique platform utilizing Site Core (New Vendor) as the single content management system. Managed 2 work streams, tasks and schedule, financial and resources, purchasing and requisitions, change requests, vendor relations and back up for the Program Manager at monthly reporting meetings to high level stakeholders and sponsors. Utilized Agile development tools including Jira. Utilized both waterfall and Agile methodologies.
- www.mayoclinic.org/espanol Mayo Clinic Spanish Language Website: Served as project manager on a mini site on the existing Mayo Clinic.org site to accommodate Spanish speaking visitors who were seeking appointments at Mayo Clinic. The project was the first non-English web site and was used as a model for the web site to be developed in Arabic. We delivered on time and within budget.
- <u>DAHLC.mayoclinic.org</u> Dan Abrahms Healthy Living Center -Led the development team
  to complete expansion of Mayo Clinic's state-of-the-art employee fitness center
  website. Site completed on budget, on time and within scope and launched in alignment
  with the launch of the marketing campaign on time and on budget
- Web Accessibility Guideline Project: The goal was to ensure Mayo Clinic's websites adhered to the guidelines as outlined by the WAI (Web Accessibility Initiative) for users with special needs. As project manager for a team of developers we identified and addressed areas needing improvement and implementing the most important updates to guarantee Mayo's Websites were compliant before the mandatory deadline. We delivered the set of policies, procedures and guidelines for the design and development of the future Mayo Clinic websites to ensure the site was accessible.
- 150years.mayoclinic.org: A high visibility website to support the extensive marketing program announcing Mayo Clinic's 150<sup>th</sup> anniversary. This site pioneered Mayo Clinic's first online donation form working with a new vendor, Blackbaud.
- Various other web projects including B2B and department sub sites

## Product Manager (1999 to 2008)

- Succeeded in improving response rates and functionality of subscription management programs
  utilizing A/B testing of various marketing collateral. As product manager, I led publication teams
  in the development of 12 new book products and 22 marketing pamphlets to promote sales. I
  managed print vendors, mailing and distribution facilities as well as fulfillment. Served as Project
  Manager for new books and other publications.
- Led database upgrade to new vendor to improve fulfillment and subscription management.
   Combined customer databases to allow for cross promotion of products and near real time reporting
- Managed outside vendor to build Mayo Clinic's first e-commerce website, an online store, to sell Mayo's' publications to the general public. Successfully launched the website and set the stage for future websites. Store.mayoclinic.com
- Redesigned and tested a new direct mailing format. Utilized current copy but changed one design feature. New flyer increased response rate by 8%-a huge lift for direct mail.

#### **Education & Certifications**

P.M.P. Project Management Professional, Project Management Institute

C.S.M. Certified Scrum Master, Scrum Alliance

M.B.A. Management, University of St. Thomas (St. Paul, MN)

B.B.A. West Texas A&M (Canyon, TX)

#### **Technical Proficiencies**

**Platforms:** Windows

Methodology: In House Custom IT Project Management Process based on PMBOK process, Agile

(Scrum), and Waterfall

**Tools:** MS Office Suites including Excel, SharePoint, Microsoft Project and Server, Clarity,

RTC, Jira (some experience) Rally and others